Finding Aid for the Russell Birdwell Papers LSC.0114
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 5. Office
  - 5.2 Other
    Contains items pertaining to the administration of Birdwell's office.
    - 530 Park Lease, ca. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Appointments, Calls, and Task Lists, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Appointments, Calls, and Task Lists, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Christmas gifts, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Contacts, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Contacts, ca. 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Expenses, ca. 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Expenses, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gift lists and correspondence, ca. 1936-1942 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Job applications, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Job applications, ca. 1939-1940 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Job applications, ca. 1941 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Job applications, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Job applications, ca. 1944 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Notes, ca. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Office promotions, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Publicity wires, 1947 January 6 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Wires, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wires, ca. 1941 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Wires, ca. 1940 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Wires, ca. 1940 (Box 31, Folder 12)
- 6. Miscellaneous
  Contains a wide variety of materials of personal and professional interest to Birdwell.
  - No Subseries assigned
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. The American Motion Picture, 1941 January 11 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Advertising Readership and Cost, 1941 December (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Aldridge, Kay--Clipping, 1941 October 24 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - American Weekly--Advertising materials, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Are We Essential?--Advertisement, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Ayres, Lew--Clipping, 1944 May 20 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Backstage Hollywood--Prospectus, 1939 June 28 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Bank of America. Facts That Concern You in Legislation, Taxation, Court Decisions, Government Rulings, and in Other Fields Affecting Property and the Administration of Estates, 1941 June (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Biddle, Margaret. "The Women of England", 1941 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Typescript
    - British propaganda, ca. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - British War Relief concert--Program, 1941 August 23 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Brown, Don Evan--Memorial, 1944 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Camilla Lucas art catalog, 1947 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Cessna advertisement, ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Chaney, Lon, Jr.--Clipping, 1932 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Community Builder, 1928 March-July (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Vol. 1, no. 4 (2 copies) and vol. 2, no. 2
    - Congressional investigation of Communism in Hollywood--Clippings, ca. 1940 August (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Contemporary China: A Reference Digest, 1941 December-1942 February (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Culver City-Hollywood publicity stunt, ca. 1937 October (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Current Biography--pages, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Daily Mail--Transatlantic Edition, 1944 March-July (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Decoration and Service Ribbons--Clipping, 1945 February 18 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Eastman, Joseph B. "Featherbed Rules," Railroad Manpower, and the T.P. and W., 1943 May 7 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - El Palacio, vol. 47, no. 8, 1940 August (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - English actors and war, ca. 1940 (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Exploitation--general, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Explore Europe from Belgium and Luxembourg, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Farrow, John--Clippings and correspondence, 1939 May-June (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Fight for Freedom, Inc., ca. 1941 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Fight for Freedom, Inc.--Advertising, ca. 1941 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Film Guide, vol. 4, no. 2, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Flying--selected pages, 1943 December (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Flynn, Edward--Clipping, 1940 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Four Star data, undated (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - Gas Rationing--Appeal for additional ration, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - General Motors--News from the Production Front, 1943 April (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - G-Man stunt--Clipping, 1936 January 31 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Ham and Eggs bill, 1939 July-August (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Harper's Bazaar-Insurance agent advertisements, ca. 1943 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Harry Oliver's Desert Rat Scrap Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Helicopters--Magazine clipping, 1943 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hohner Harmonica--Pamphlet, undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Hollywood Anti-Nazi League, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hollywood Reporter, 1945 January 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Honduras, ca. 1935-1936 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Industrial films, ca. 1939 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Industrial films, ca. 1939 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Jews in Germany--Clipping, 1938 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Johnson, Nunnally--Clippings, 1940 August 19-September 23 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Kay, Julius--Clipping, 1945 February 23 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Lackey, Al--Cartoons, 1943 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Le Gallienne--The Illusion of War, undated (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Lemon growers--Clipping, 1939 May 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Letters to LIFE about Frank Sinatra, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Loew's suit, 1938 November-December (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Lord's Last Supper (work of art), undated (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Luce, Henry--clippings, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Lyons, Gerald, 1945 October (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1943 July, November (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous picture captions, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous publicity, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Motion picture data, 1938 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Mount Diablo, California: Aeroplane View Scenic Boulevard, ca. 1915 (Box 57, Folder 23)
    - Murphy, Dudley--Clipping, 1943 November 15 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Nazis, 1942 March 8 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper correspondents covering Hollywood, undated (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Operations of Special Service--Chart, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Pan American, ca. 1939 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Pan American and Clipper Ship brochures, ca. 1938 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Panzer Rushes--clipping, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Partial narrative by unknown person, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Philippine Islands, ca. 1939-1940 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Press releases about staff, ca. 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Press releases about staff, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Press releases about staff, ca. 1946 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Producers file ("confidential"), undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Publicity data, 1941 March 29 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Publicity for President's Birthday Ball, 1938 January (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Publicity ideas, ca. 1942-1946 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Railroad propaganda, 1938 December 17 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Republic amphibian Seabee--Prints, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Ritz Idea: The Story of a Great Hotel, by Lucius Beebe, 1936 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, speech--Clipping, 1943 January 8 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Safety Sun, 1939 November-1940 July (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Sample programs and fonts, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - San Dimas Rattler, 1944 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Scientific Subjects and Authorities as Recommended by the National Research Council, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Selznick Co. parade permit, 1937 December 10 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Selznick, D. O.--Chamber of Commerce membership card, ca. 1940 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Sequoia Hi-Lites, 1944 November-December (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sight Seeing in Costa Rica, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Staff publicity, ca. 1943-1946 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Straub, Ruth--Diary of a Bataan Nurse, 1942 September 30-October 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Tap Root (CPS Camp 59, Elkton, Oregon), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Thalberg, Irving--biography, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Trails Magazine, 1937 Autumn (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Train tickets, 1941 September 4 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Propaganda, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Propaganda, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Propaganda--Speech by Archibald MacLeish, 1942 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - War bond sales--Clipping, 1942 August 20 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Westward (Kaiser Steel), 1950 January-1951 July (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Windsor, Duke of--Newspaper clipping, 1945 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Women's Voluntary Services (W.V.S.)--Clippings, 1942 April-November (Box 1, Folder 19)